Jacob Seidenberg Additional Files 5194
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Jacob Seidenberg Additional Files
1957-1971
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Seidenberg, Jacob
5194
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Arbitration files of Jacob Seidenberg
5602110
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 24, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 21, 2017
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Jacob Seidenberg (1914-1996) was a government official who specialized in labor arbitration and non-discrimination contracts, and wrote extensively on labor law and negotiations. He graduated from Temple University in 1937 and received a law degree from the University of Pennsylvania Law School in 1941. During the 1940s he was an attorney with the U.S. War Department, the National War Labor Board and the National Wage Stabilization Board. In 1948 he went to graduate school at Cornell University, from which he earned his Ph.D. in industrial and labor relations in 1951. In 1951 he joined the staff of the President's Committee on Government Contract Compliance. The Committee was abolished by President Dwight D. Eisenhower in August 1953 by Executive Order 10479 and was succeeded by the President's Committee on Government Contracts. Seidenberg was appointed Executive Director of the new committee and served until January 1960 when he resigned to become a full-time labor arbitrator. The Committee was responsible for enforcing non-discrimination clauses in government contracts, worked with private businesses to help them overcome job discrimination, and developed educational programs against ethnic and racial discrimination. The chairman was Vice President Richard Nixon, and the vice chairman was Secretary of Labor James P. Mitchell. In later years Seidenberg served on a number of boards of inquiry involving labor disputes. From 1970 to 1975 he was chairman of the Federal Services Impasses Panel which settled deadlocks in federal labor negotiations.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5031 A&B: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5032: Jacob Seidenberg Injunction Study 5175: Jacob Seidenberg Taft-Hartley Maritime Dispute Records 5217: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Case Files 5229: Jacob Seidenberg Additional records 5468: Jacob Seidenberg Arbitration files 5519: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5571: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5605: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Records 5635: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5666: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5706: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5756: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5773: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5808: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5900: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5935: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files 5953: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Records 5988: Jacob Seidenberg Additional Arbitration Files
Arbitration, Industrial -- United States -- Sources; Seidenberg, Jacob
5602110
- Award No. 1, PL No. 239, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Award No. 2 PL No. 239, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Award No. 3 PL No. 239, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Public Law Board No. 86 Award No. 3, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Award No. 4 Public Law Board No. 239, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Award No. 5 Public Law Board No. 239, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Award No. 6 Public Law Board No. 239, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Award No. 7 Public Law Board No. 239, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Special Board of Adjustment No, 558, Submission and Awards 1 of 2, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Special Board of Adjustment No, 558, Submission and Awards 2 of 2, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Awards, Public Law Board No. 20, United Transportation Union (E) New York Central, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Original Awards, Special Board of Adjustment No. 196, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Awards, Public Law Board No. 207, Milwaukee United Transportation Union (T), Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Awards No. 287, 288. 289, Special Board of Adjustment No. 100, United Transportation Union 1214, Carrier 45-402 1 of 2, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Awards No. 287, 288. 289, Special Board of Adjustment No. 100, United Transportation Union 1214, Carrier 45-402 2 of 2, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Award No. 290, Special Board of Adjustment No. 100, United Transportation Union 1279, Carrier 44-755, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Award No. 291, Special Board of Adjustment No. 100, United Transportation Union 1261, 44-750, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Special Board of Adjustment No. 100, Award No. 292, United Transportation Union 1263, 46-1042, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Special Board of Adjustment No. 100. Award No. 293, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Award No. 294, Special Board of Adjustment No. 100, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Award No. 295, Special Board of Adjustment No. 100, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Award No. 296, Special Board of Adjustment No. 100, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Award No. 1, Public Law Board No. 356, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Award No. 2, Public Law Board No. 356, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Awards No. 3 - 4, Public Law Board No. 356, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Award No. 5, Public Law Board No. 356, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Award No. 6, Public Law Board No. 356, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Award No. 7, Public Law Board No. 356, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Award No. 8, Public Law Board No. 356, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Public Law Board No. 207, Milwaukee versus BRT, Case No. 1 and 2, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Public Law Board No. 207, Award No. 3-4 Milwaukee, BRT, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Public Law Board, Award No. 5, Milwaukee vs. BRT 1 of 2, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Awards No. 6-12, Public Law Board No. 207 1 of 2, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Awards No. 6-12, Public Law Board No. 207 2 of 2, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Award No. 13, Public Law Board No. 207, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Award No. 14, Public Law Board No. 207, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Award No. 15, Public Law Board No. 207, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Award No. 17, Public Law Board No. 207, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Award No. 1, Docket 40403, Public Law Board No. 217, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Award No. 2, Public Law Board No. 217, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Award No. 3, Public Law Board No. 217, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Award No. 4, Public Law Board No. 217, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Public Law Board No. 184, Atlanta and West Point vs. BLFE 1 of 2, 1957-1966 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Public Law Board No. 184, Atlanta and West Point vs. BLFE 2 of 2, 1957-1966 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Public Law Board No. 107, BRT vs. PATH, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Award No. 1, Special Board of Adjustment No. 740, Penn Central vs. BLE, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Award No. 3, Special Board of Adjustment No. 729, NYC vs. BRT, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Award No.1, Special Board of Adjustment No. 729, NYC vs. BRT, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Award No. 5, Public Law Board No. 83, Case No. 871-172, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Award No. 6, Public Law Board No. 83, Case No. 871-171, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Award No. 7, Public Law Board No. 83, Case No. 871-175, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Award No. 8, Public Law Board No. 83, Case No. 742-218, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Award No. 9,, Public Law Board No. 83, Case No. 742-226, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Award No. 10, Public Law Board No. 83, Case No. 742-227, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Award No. 11,, Public Law Board No. 83, Case No. 957-275, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Award No. 12, Public Law Board No. 83, Case No. 957-283, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Award No. 13, Public Law Board No. 83, Case No. 957-287, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Award No. 14, Public Law Board No. 83, Case No. 957-298, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Award No. 3, Special Board of Adjustment No. 743, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Award No. 4, Special Board of Adjustment No. 743, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Award 5-6, Special Board of Adjustment No. 743, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Award No. 7, Special Board of Adjustment No. 743, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Awards No. 107 and 108, Special Board of Adjustment No. 196, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Award No. 1, Public Law Board No. 83, Case No. 871-148, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Award No. 2, Public Law Board No. 83, Case No. 871-150, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Award No. 3, Public Law Board No. 3, Case No. 871-163, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Award No. 4, Public Law Board No. 83, Case No. 871-166, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Award No. 1, Public Law Board No. 86, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Award No. 2, Public Law Board No. 86, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Award No. 4, Public Law Board No. 86, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Award No. 5, Public Law Board No. 86, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Award No. 6, Public Law Board No. 86, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Awards No. 7,6,9, Public Law Board No. 86, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Award No. 10, Public Law Board No. 86, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Award No. 11, Public Law Board No. 86, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Award No. 12, Public Law Board No. 86, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Award No. 13, Public Law Board No. 86, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Award No. 14, Public Law Board No. 86, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Award No. 15, Public Law Board No. 86, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Award No. 16, Public Law Board No. 86, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Award No. 117, Public Law Board No. 86, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Award No. 18, Public Law Board No. 86, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Award No. 19, Public Law Board No. 86, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Award No. 20, Public Law Board No. 86, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Award No. 21, Public Law Board No. 86, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Award No. 22, Public Law Board No. 86, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 48)